Hold on, Aika. Wait for me.
等一下 爱华 你等等我
Don't! Don't come any closer! What an annoyance.
不要 你别过来 你很烦耶
Why are you so mean to me?
你别对我这么凶嘛
I would not be mean to you if it were not for your annoyance!
要不是因为你太烦人 我才不会凶你
Huh? Am I that annoying?
我有这么顾人怨吗
Of course! Stop bothering me!
当然啊 你别再缠着我了
I can't stand that.
那我可受不了
I can't stand you either.
我才受不了你呢
My name is Sajo Wataru.
我的名字叫佐城涉
I am an ordinary male high school student.
一个普通的男高中生
If I have any traits,
如果要说我有什么特征
it might be that half of the people at school
应该就是学校里有一半的人
think I am a stalker.
都把我当成跟踪狂吧
Her name is Natsukawa Aika.
她的名字叫夏川爱华
I think of her as a perfect goddess
对我来说 她简直无可挑剔
who has been bestowed by heaven.
是上天赐给我的完美女神
I have a strong crush on her
我深深迷恋着她
and hope to date her one day.
盼望有朝一日能跟她交往
So, I keep going after her day after day.
所以才会天天对她展开热烈追求
Hey, are you okay?
喂 你没事吧
I'm fine.
我没事
All of this happened because you kept bothering me.
都是因为你老是缠着我 才会变成这样
So stay away from me.
你别再靠近我了
You're right.
你说得对
I will do that.
我会照做的
(Dreaming Boy is a Realist, The)
《满怀美梦的少年是现实主义者》
(I like you, please date with me)
(我喜欢你 跟我在一起吧)
-Yesterday's club activity… -Ah, it went well.
-昨天的社团… -还算顺利…
Sajo, good morning.
早啊 小佐城
Good morning.
啊 早安
Sajo, I heard you got your comeuppance early in the morning?
小佐城 听说你一大早就遭到报应了
Comeuppance? Oh, that.
报应 那个啊
Kei, enough.
圭 你别说了
Keeping doing this will only make Aika hate you more.
你再继续这样下去 小爱只会越来越讨厌你哦
Kei, enough, don't say anything.
好了啦 圭你别说了
Hmm, yeah, I think so too.
是啊 我也这么觉得
Sajo, are you sick?
小佐城 你该不会发烧了吧
No, I'm fine.
没有啊
-But… -Everyone, take your seats.
-可是… -大家回位子上坐好
Oh, Sajo.
哎呀 佐城同学
It is unusual to see you sitting quietly in your seat.
难得看到你乖乖坐在位子上耶
Is that so?
是吗
Yeah, aren't you always looking at Natsukawa?
是啊 平常你不都一直追着夏川同学跑吗
Well…
这个嘛
Hey, you! Stop pestering me.
你就别再缠着我了
No, I just wanted to go to the bathroom.
不是 我只是想去洗手间
Is that so?
这…这样啊
What's wrong with you, Sajo?
你怎么了啊 佐城
What happened between you two?
你们两个怎么了啊
Did you have a fight?
该不会是吵架了吧
It's nothing. We always fight, don't we?
我们吵架又不是什么稀奇的事
Well, that's true.
你这么说也没错啦
But isn't it Natsukawa who usually gets angry?
不过平常不都只是夏川同学在生气吗
But no matter how angry she is, you always pester her, don't you?
无论她怎么生气 你都还是会继续缠着她
-Well, yeah. -What do you mean by that?
-算是吧 -什么叫“算是吧”
I'm not in the mood for that today.
今天我没那个心情
I feel odd.
总觉得哪里不对劲
By the way,
话说
can you tell that I like Aika?
你们看得出来我喜欢爱华吗
What are you talking about? Aren't you infatuated with her?
你在说什么啊 你不是超级迷恋她吗
That's true. I adore her and want to spread the word about her everywhere.
对吧 我喜欢她 喜欢到想到处宣扬她的好
Hey, what is up with the crush at this point?
喂喂 你是在发什么花痴啊
Spread the word?
宣扬
Hey.
欸
Hmm? Are you calling me?
嗯 你叫我吗
Ah? You must have heard wrong.
啊 你听错了吧
Oh, I see.
哦 也是
Where are you going?
你…你要去哪
Huh? I'm going to the cafeteria.
嗯 我要去学餐的商店
-Seriously? -What's wrong?
-不会吧 -干嘛
Usually, you would say,
平常你都会说
"Aika, Aika. Let's eat together."
“爱华爱华 我们一起吃饭吧”
"Your lunch looks delicious today too."
“你今天的便当看起来也好好吃”
"Are you going to let me have a bite"?
“啊 难道你要让我尝一口吗”
And you just shamelessly pester her.
你都会这样厚着脸皮贴上去
Just go if you're going to go.
你要去就快去
Or you won't have enough time.
不然时间就来不及了
Is he okay?
那家伙还好吧
Is he abnormal after being rejected so many times?
莫非是被拒绝太多次 所以头壳坏掉了
Hang in there.
你要坚强地活下去啊
How should I put it…?
怎么回事呢
Hey.
那个…
You're Sajo, right?
你是佐城同学吧
You mistook me for someone else.
你…你认错人了吧
How could I mistake you for someone else?
怎么可能会认错呢
Oh! You can actually recognize me!
哇 你居然认得出来
I am the well-known Sajo Wataru.
我就是赫赫有名的佐城涉
As a reward for recognizing me, I'll give you this red ginger.
这个红姜丝就送给你 当作是认出我的奖励
What? I don't want it.
我才不要咧
So, who are you?
话说 你是谁啊
Huh? Oh, it's normal that you don't know me.
也是啦 你不认识我很正常
I'm Aizawa Rena from the next class.
我是隔壁班的蓝泽玲奈
Aizawa Rena, huh?
蓝泽玲奈同学…
Why did you come to see me specifically?
你特地来找我有什么事吗
Have a guess.
你猜猜啊
What a hassle.
哇 真麻烦
You're so rude.
你好过分哦
Sajo, bye.
佐城同学 再会咯
(Dreaming Boy is a Realist, The)
《满怀美梦的少年是现实主义者》
Sajo. You jerk.
佐城你这小子
Ouch! I surrender, I surrender!
好痛 我投降啦
What are you doing?
你干嘛啦
I've already experienced extreme wrestling games with my sister.
这种摔角游戏 光我姐就够我让好受的了
Someone is looking for you.
有人找你啦
She said she's waiting for you.
她说她在等你
Good morning, Sajo.
早啊 佐城同学
You're Aizawa from yesterday, right?
你是昨天的…蓝泽同学
The one who suddenly talked to me.
突然找我搭话的那个
What do you mean? Don't you like that?
什么啊 你是说昨天你很不情愿吗
Not really.
倒也不是
I was surprised when a cute girl came up to talk to me.
只是突然被可爱的女生搭话 所以我吓了一跳而已
You already have Natsukawa, don't you?
你这小子明明已经有夏川了
Natsukawa is my goddess.
夏川是我的女神
So what's the deal with this girl?
那这女生又是怎么回事
Um, what do you want from me?
呃 你找我干嘛
Well, have a guess.
这个嘛 你说呢
-You jerk! -Wait a minute.
-你这家伙 -等…等下
-Sajo. -Ah, sorry.
-小佐城 -抱歉
Uh… Aika?
那个…爱华
What's up?
什么事
No, nothing.
不 没什么
I'm on duty today.
今天我是值日生
Sajo. You are so popular.
你还真是艳福不浅啊 小佐城
I'll go help Aika.
我去帮小爱的忙
Oh no, did she misunderstand me?
糟糕 我是不是害她误会了
Hmm… Aizawa?
那个 蓝泽同学
Just call me Rena.
叫我玲奈就好
And then?
什么事呢
-Awesome! -You're amazing!
-太好了 -接得漂亮
Sajo! The ball is coming!
佐城 球传过去了
Hey, Sajo! What are you daydreaming about?
喂佐城 你发什么呆啊
Sorry, sorry.
抱歉抱歉
You are so lame.
你真是逊毙了
Ashida? What do you want?
是芦田啊 你有什么事吗
Nothing. I am just here to say hello to you, you flirtatious scumbag.
没事 只是来跟爱拈花惹草的渣男打声招呼
Scumbag.
渣男…
Weren't you chatting with other girls happily?
你不是跟其他女生聊得很开心吗
No, it's because…
没啊 那是因为…
But who can resist Aizawa?
不过 谁叫她是蓝泽同学呢
It seems even you can't resist her charm.
看来就连你也挡不住她的诱惑
Is she famous?
她很有名吗
Aizawa has a loving boyfriend in the second grade.
蓝泽同学有个二年级的男朋友 他们感情超好
Many people know about this.
很多人都知道这件事
According to my intelligence network, they started dating in junior high.
根据我的情报网 他们从国一就开始交往了
Intelligence network?
情…情报网
Why does it sound so scary?
听起来怎么有点吓人
Ah, but you're really suitable to be a spy.
啊 不过你的确满适合当间谍
Her boyfriend is a year older than us, in class B Grade 2.
她男朋友大我们一届 好像是二年B班吧
He has short hair and he is quite handsome.
头发偏短 算是清爽型的帅哥
How did you get this picture?
是说你去哪弄来的照片啊
Shinomiya is my type! I want to be scolded by her.
我喜欢四之宫学姐那一型的 好想被她狠狠训斥
I got you.
我懂
I also wanted to be scolded by her or have her stare at me without saying anything.
我想被她狠狠骂一顿 或是被她一声不吭地瞪着
By the way, the vice president seems to be this type too.
对了 副会长好像也是这种类型
Oh, kindred spirit.
你真是同道中人啊
-Arimura, how about you? -As for me…
-有村你呢 -我嘛…
It should be Natsukawa in the first grade.
应该是一年级的夏川吧
What are you thinking with a straight face?
你板着一张脸是在想什么
I am thinking there are all kinds of people in this world.
我只是在想这世上还真是什么人都有
I agree.
我同意
Why do you look at me when you say that?
你为什么要边说边看着我的脸
Because there's a weirdo right in front of me.
因为我眼前的人就很奇葩啊
Stop it.
你们别吵了
I feel like you've been a bit strange lately, Sajo.
我总觉得小佐城你最近怪怪的
-What? -I got it.
-怎样啊 -我懂了
I suppose you care a little bit about Aizawa.
你一定是有点在意蓝泽同学吧
You…
你…
But it's true.
确实是这样没错啦
I have a question for you guys.
嗯…我有个问题想问你们
-What is it? -A question?
-什么 -问题
Sajo.
佐…城…同…学
Are you busy now?
你现在在忙吗
Sorry to interrupt.
打扰了
What's the matter?
呃 你找我有事吗
I just wanted to chat with you.
我只是想找你聊聊天
So, you don't have anything specific?
意思是说其实你没什么事吗
Yeah, sort of.
嗯 算是吧
Let's chat then.
那我们就来聊聊吧
Why did you break up with your ex-boyfriend?
你为什么会跟前男友分手咧
Huh? How do you know about that?
咦你怎么会知道这件事
And why do you start by asking me such a question?
而且哪有人会突然问这种问题
Kei.
圭
What's the matter?
有什么关系嘛
Anyway, you're already with Sajo now, aren't you?
反正你现在已经搭上小佐城了吧
Huh? Actually…
什么 其实…
Probably because I am not perfect, right?
应该是因为我有不好的地方吧
Really? You're so strong.
真的假的 你真坚强
The guy who dumped you clearly has poor taste.
跟你分手的前男友也太没眼光了
But anyway, now you have Sajo.
但反正现在你已经有小佐城了
It's right to break up with that kind of ex-boyfriend.
跟那种前男友分手是正确的抉择
Kei! What are you talking about?
圭 你在说什么啊
Because Aizawa is such a good girl, and he didn't even cherish her.
像蓝泽同学这么好的女孩 那个人居然不珍惜
-It's outrageous! Terrible! -Don't…
-实在太过分了 好差劲 -不要…
Could you stop criticizing my ex-boyfriend?
可以请你不要说我前男友的坏话吗
Wait.
等等…
Oh no! Are you okay?
糟糕 你没事吧
Don't come over.
别过来
Sorry.
对…对不起
I'm really sorry about that.
刚才真是不好意思
Why are you apologizing to me?
为什么你要跟我道歉
You're right about that.
被你这么一说好像也对
I was not expecting her to be so rude.
我没想到她说话这么没分寸
Sajo.
佐城同学
You rarely mention Natsukawa around me.
你跟我在一起的时候 好像不常提起夏川同学耶
Don't bring up another girl in front of a girl.
不在女生面前提起别的女生
That's what I learned from my dating experience.
这是我从恋爱经验里学到的
You have dating experience too?
你也正在谈恋爱啊
I don't know if I can count it.
我也不知道算不算啦
After all, I haven't been very successful.
毕竟都没成功过
But you do like Natsukawa, right?
但你喜欢夏川同学对吧
You know that too?
很明显吗
Everyone knows it now.
这件事已经人尽皆知了
That's true.
也对
But maybe I should give up.
不过 也许我该收手了
Because I've been rejected too many times.
我被拒绝了太多次
My passion is waning.
总觉得内心的热情好像逐渐消退了
Is it? Right.
啊 原来是这么回事
How about you? Have you ever been in a relationship?
你呢 有谈过恋爱…
Oh, sorry.
啊 抱歉
I apologized to you for that, and now I'm asking such a sensitive question.
我才刚跟你道过歉 现在又问这么敏感的问题
"She's super cute."
“她超可爱”
He said so.
他是这么跟我说的
So we broke up.
所以我跟他分手了
I could tell
从他的话语之中
from what he said was not what he meant,
我明白那种并不是真心的喜欢
but I still could not accept it.
但我还是不能接受
Oh, well.
啊 嗯…
So I decided to let him feel the same way.
我因为想让他感受一下同样的滋味
That's why I came to find you.
所以才来找你
I am indeed overthinking. It's too bad that it is a waste of time.
我不仅胡思乱想还白费力气 真是糟透了
A waste of time?
白费力气吗
Aizawa, listen.
蓝泽 你听我说
In fact, before I met Aika,
其实我在遇到爱华之前
I was dumped by another girl.
曾被另一个女孩狠狠地拒绝
Huh? You?
咦 你吗
Yes, it was back in junior high school.
对 在我国中的时候
"You are not handsome or fashionable.
“你这么土里土气”
How dare you say you like me"?
“凭你这长相也敢喜欢我”
Anyway, I was dumped miserably.
总之我被甩得很惨
In the end, her boyfriend came and beat me up.
最后还被她男朋友揍了一顿
Aika walked past me from behind
就在我被揍飞的时候
as the punches sent me flying, and I fell right into her chest.
爱华从我身后走过 我就一头栽进了她的胸口
Aika slapped me while screaming.
爱华尖叫着 同时赏了我一巴掌
-So I fell for her. -Why?
-于是我就爱上她了 -为什么啊
Aika heard everything
爱华听了事情的经过
and told them off for me.
她替我教训了他们
She said that the worst thing they can do is make fun of someone's feelings.
说嘲笑别人的心意非常差劲
From that moment on, I could only see Aika.
那次之后 我的眼里就只有爱华了
I see.
这样啊…
But all that just now was nonsense.
刚才那段都是我瞎掰的
But Aika would definitely do that.
但爱华一定会那么做的
At first, I might have liked her at first sight.
起初我对她可能只是一见钟情
But what really made me fall in love with her
但最终让我心动的原因
was how sweet she was
是我难以忘怀她第一次
when she first reached out to me. I will never forget that.
向我伸出手时那温柔的模样
Is it? I see.
原来是这样啊
After that, I became Aika's supporter.
所以我就成为了爱华的粉丝
Huh, supporter?
粉丝…
Natsukawa Aika is the idol of all mankind! A symbol of hope! A goddess!
夏川爱华是全人类的偶像 是希望的象征 是女神
So I have decided to spread the word about Aika's good points!
所以我决定了 我要把爱华的优点宣扬出去
Hold on, hold on! Sajo.
等等 佐城同学
Don't you want to date Natsukawa?
你不是想跟夏川同学交往吗
If I keep approaching her, I'll only bring her trouble.
再这样下去只会造成她的困扰
But that does not mean I will stop caring about her.
但这不代表我对她的感情会消失
Even if I can't date her,
就算无法跟她在一起
I'll support her in my own way.
我也要用我的方式支持她
From now on, as the one who's been dumped,
今后我要作为一个被甩的人
I will silently protect her happiness from afar.
从远处默默守护她的幸福
Although this might still be a bit annoying.
虽然这样可能还是有点烦人
It is a bit annoying.
是有点烦人呢
I see.
这样啊
So there's such a way.
原来还有这种方法
I feel like I've cheered up.
我好像打起精神来了
-Although I don't quite understand. -That's good.
-虽然我也说不出个所以然 -好
I'll teach Ashida a lesson.
我会去教训一下芦田
No need, no need.
你不用这样啦
I think Ashida is just protecting Natsukawa.
我想芦田同学也只是想保护夏川同学
Protecting Natsukawa?
你说她想保护夏川
Yeah, she probably realized I had ulterior motives.
嗯 她应该是察觉到我有什么意图
But I won't do anything weird anymore.
不过我不会再做奇怪的事了
Aizawa.
蓝泽
Actually, not just Arimura,
其实不只是有村学长
all men have this problem.
男人都有这种通病
I understand.
我知道啦
Morning, Aika.
早啊 小爱
Oh, morning.
早安啊
Look over there.
你看那边
That's Rena and her boyfriend.
那是小玲奈跟她男朋友
-They made up. -It seems so.
-他们已经复合了啊 -好像是耶
Ah, poor thing.
唉 真可怜啊
I'm talking about Sajo.
我是说小佐城
He was not only rejected by you, but he was also dumped by Aizawa.
他不仅被你拒绝 现在又被蓝泽同学甩了
Yeah.
是啊
Ah, what a nice dream.
啊 我真是作了一场好梦
What's that supposed to mean?
这算什么
Isn't it great to have a good memory?
创造一段不错的回忆就够了吗
I knew she had other purposes.
我早就知道她有其他目的了
I figured I might as well have fun before she came clean to me.
所以决定在她跟我坦白前 自己先好好享受一番
What's so fun about it?
这算什么享受
Every man's ideal type is a girl like Aizawa,
像蓝泽这种看似有些调皮
who looks a little bit naughty
实际上好相处又爱撒娇的女孩
but is actually kind and caring.
可是所有男人的理想类型啊
Getting to spend time with such a girl is a reward for me.
能跟这样的女孩相处一段时间 简直就是一种奖赏啊
That's disgusting.
太恶心了吧
Anyway, as everything is settled now, it is good, right?
反正事情已经圆满解决了 这样不是很好吗
You really don't mind?
你真的…不介意吗
If I were hated, that would be another story.
要是被讨厌的话就另当别论了
But I never had any expectations from the beginning.
反正我从一开始就不抱期待
You're really inexplicable.
真是莫名其妙
Well, no wonder.
我想也是啦…
What's wrong with you? You seem a bit strange.
你怎么了好像有点反常耶
I feel like I was weirder before.
我反而觉得以前的自己才奇怪
What's wrong, Sajo? Why so serious?
怎么了佐城一脸严肃样
Do you feel Natsukawa's hatred now?
夏川终于开始真的讨厌你了吗
Do not get in the way of our divorce talks.
我们正在商量离婚事宜 你们少插嘴
Divorce?
什么离婚啊
-What's wrong? -Have you split up?
-什么嘛 -撕破脸了吗
Shut up!
闭嘴
Just agree to date me.
你就答应跟我交往吧
I'm so stupid. We're not a good match at all.
我好蠢 仔细想想我们根本就不配嘛
Excuse me.
打扰了
Um, you can sit there.
呃 你就坐这里吧
Oh, it's okay. How did you know where I live?
没关系…不过你怎么知道地址
I found out from the boy who stayed for club activities.
是留下来参加社团的男同学告诉我的
You must have something to tell me.
你是…有话要跟我说吧
After all, you would not just show up at my house.
不然你也不会没事就来我家
Well, my house is empty now.
那个…现在我家没人
No! I didn't mean anything else!
啊不 我没有其他意思
I know.
我知道
What's wrong with you lately?
你最近是怎么了
Huh? Is there something strange about me?
什么我有怪怪的吗
If we are talking about strange, you have always been pretty strange.
要说怪的话…你一直都怪怪的
You seem less strange lately, which makes you stranger.
就是因为你最近不奇怪 所以才觉得怪怪的
What does that mean?
什么意思啊
You're usually very indifferent.
你平常不是都很旁若无人嘛
And you keep coming up to me.
而且总是对我很主动
In short, you're annoying.
你也知道就是很烦人嘛
Can't I disagree?
你是要我附和你吗
But lately you have stopped pestering me.
可是最近你完全不缠着我了
You don't follow me like you used to.
也不像以前一样跟着我
It's like you suddenly became sensible!
该怎么说呢 就好像突然变得很懂事
Well, Aika.
爱华 我…
What's up?
怎样
I like you, please date with me.
我喜欢你 跟我在一起吧
What? What are you talking about?
啊 你在说什么啊
How could I possibly agree in this situation?
在这种情况下我怎么可能会答应你
Mm, I knew it.
嗯 我就知道
I'm sorry, Natsukawa.
对不起 夏川
After all this, you…
干嘛突然…你叫我夏川
Anyone would find it disgusting
明明已经被你拒绝了无数次
if a man who has been turned down
却一直对你死缠烂打的男人
many times keeps bothering you.
正常情况下谁都会觉得恶心吧
Why are you suddenly saying this?
你干嘛突然说这些
-It's just… -I'm back!
-就是… -我回来了
I'm so tired.
累死我了
Hey, get me something to drink. Wataru brought a girl home!
喂 去给我拿点喝的… 阿涉带女孩子回家了
And she's so cute!
也太可爱了吧
Is this your girlfriend?
这该不会是你的女朋友吧
No, no.
不是啦
She just came to talk to me about something.
她只是来找我谈点事情
I'll walk you out.
我送你回去
I'll walk you out?
送她回去
Don't keep interrupting.
你不要一直插嘴啦
Are you in student council?
你…是学生会的…
Yes, there's just too much work.
没错 事情有够多的
I'm sorry about what the vice president did just now.
我们家那个副会长让你见笑了
I didn't know before.
我完全不知情
-About just now… -Huh?
-刚才的事… -什么
What did you want to say
你刚才那句话还没说完
after "it's just"?
是什么
You had something to say
刚才在你姐姐回家前
before your sister came back, right?
你不是有话要说吗
I have caused you much trouble.
我之前造成你很多困扰
So I want to say that I won't bother you anymore.
我想跟你说 以后我不会再缠着你了
From now on, as an ordinary classmate, thank you for your help.
以后我们就是普通的同班同学了 请多多指教
What do you mean by that?
什么多多指教啊…
In that case,
既然如此
can you introduce me to anyone who would get along with me?
你身边有没有适合我的女性朋友 可以介绍给我
What!
你…
You're terrible!
差劲透顶
Hey, Natsukawa!
喂 夏川
Irritating, idiot!
烦死了 笨蛋
KAMIJIAMA, ICHINOSE, AIBE, SUMIYOSHI
(上岛 一之濑 相部 住吉)
SAJO, ASHIDA Hey, hey!
(佐城 芦田) 喂喂
You're not sitting with Aika anymore.
你跟小爱的座位分开了耶
Are you sad? You must be sad, right?
难过吗 很难过吧
Ah, it's a bit regrettable.
是有一点遗憾啦
Rest in peace.
节哀顺变
But this way, I won't trouble Natsukawa.
不过这样就不会让夏川困扰了
Natsukawa? Trouble?
夏川困扰
I'm about to give up.
我早就觉得差不多该收手了
So this is also a good opportunity.
所以这也算是个好机会
Oh, I see.
唉 我懂了
But you should take some responsibility.
不过你至少得负一些责任啊
Huh? Why?
嗯 为什么
Because you're always following her closely,
都是因为你总是紧紧跟着小爱
no one else can approach Aika.
害得其他人都无法接近她
Right. I'll spread the word about her then.
好 那我就大力宣扬她吧